PAVEL BOGDANOV

■ BogdanovCoding@gmail.com (312) 998-9804 Chicago, IL in BogdanovCoding BogdanovCoding

SUMMARY

Army veteran turned software developer with a genuine love for learning. Researched coding languages and taught myself Python before enrolling in a full stack coding bootcamp. Excited to leverage my leadership and technical skills in a full stack software engineering role where I can deliver high impact customer features.

SKILLS

FRAMEWORKS: Django

LANGUAGES: Python, Javascript, HTML, CSS, BASH TOOLS: GitHub, React, Selenium, Grub, Syslinux

DATABASES: PostgreSQL, SQLite

PROJECTS

Stock and forex quote API

Built an application to check the price of stocks and foreign exchange. You can type in the name of the stock symbol and get an immediate stock price. Uses an API for forex and stock quotes.

EDUCATION

Code Platoon Jan. 2020 - Apr. 2020

- Studied Python, Javascript, PostgreSQL, AWS
- Practiced agile, project management, best engineering practices
- Trained on multiple frameworks with lots of pair programming

California State University Northridge

Sept. 2014 - Nov. 2016

Studied Mechanical Engineering

EMPLOYMENT

Army July 2006 - June 2013

- Solely responsible for unit's response to chemical and biological warfare
- Trained and regularly certified entire unit (~200 people) on how to respond to a chemical or biological warfare incident
- Distributed and logged over \$1,000,000 worth of equipment to soldiers as a logistics team member
- Maintained, serviced and accounted for over \$1,000,000 worth of specialized equipment used to detect chemical attacks

Lyft, Independent Contract Driver

Dec. 2016 - Dec. 2019

- Safety oriented driver who earned and maintained a 5.0 star rating and a perfect safety record
- Logged over 10,000 rides using excellent customer service skills